A Guide to the Stafford County Records, 1819-1906
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Stafford County Records, 1819-1906
The Library of Virginia
23785
5 leaves and 20 pages
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 26 March 1952, of George H. S. King of Fredericksburg, Virginia.
Historical Information
Stafford County was named for the English county. It was formed from Westmoreland County in 1664. Part of King George County was added in 1777. The county seat is Stafford.
Many pre-Civil War court records were lost to vandalism by Union troops during the Civil War. A few volumes that record deeds, court orders, and wills exist.
Scope and Content
Stafford County, Virginia, records, 1819-1906, consisting of deeds, 1819-1848, for property in Stafford County, including in Aquia; agreements, 1847-1848, involving John H. Sutton and concerning lots and houses in Aquia; plat, 12 November 1906, for 92.112 acres in Stafford County; and a map (incomplete), n.d., of Woodstock (Aquia) and surrounding area in Stafford county.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Stafford County Court Records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm."
Stafford County is one of Virginia's Lost Records Localities. Additional Stafford County Records may be found in the Virginia Lost Records Localities Collection at the Library of Virginia. Search the Lost Records Localities Digital Collection available at Virginia Memory.
For more information and a listing of lost records localities see Lost Records research note.
Contents List
- Deed, dated 6 February 1819 and recorded 8 March 1819, for 7 lots in Woodstock (Aquia), Stafford County, from William W. Peyton to James Homes.
- Deed, dated 8 October 1841 and recorded 11 October 1841, for house and lots in Aquia from James W. Johnson to James Homes.
- Deed, dated 4 November 1842 and recorded 20 December 1842, for 500 acres in Stafford County from Charles F. Suttle to William Bayly.
- Typescript of a deed, dated and recorded 17 January 1843, for 500 acres in Stafford County from William Bayly to Nathaniel W. Ford.
- Agreement, 1 January 1848, concerning houses and lots in Aquia between John Moncure and John H. Suttle.
- Agreement, 1 January 1848, concerning houses and lots in Aquia between Thomas Franklin and John H. Suttle.
- Agreement, 17 January 1848, concerning houses and lots in Aquia between Thomas N. Towson and John H. Suttle.
- Agreement, 23 December 1847 with an additional notation dated 23 November 1849, concerning houses and lots in Aquia between Mary Homes and John H. Suttle.
- Agreement, 23 December 1847 with additional notations dated 23 November 1849 and 7 October 1852, concerning houses and lots in Aquia between Mary Homes and John H. Suttle.
- Deed, dated October 1848 and recorded 23 April 1853, for lots in Aquia from Thomas Franklin, et. al. to John H. Suttle.
- Plat, 12 November 1906, for 92.112 acres in Stafford County owned by James D. Monroe made by E. H. Randolph.
- Map (incomplete), no date, of Woodstock (Aquia) and surrounding area in Stafford county.